<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Khabardaar Podcast</title>
    <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Khabardaar Podcast</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 00:00:17 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khabardaarpodcast.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>#81 Catch Up Session</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/catch-up-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/catch-up-session/</guid>
      <description>Episode 81: And we&amp;rsquo;re back! It&amp;rsquo;s been a few months since Aparita and Baisakhi spoke to each other about Bollywood films. Physical distancing during the time of a global pandemic and other distractions kept us away from our usual Hindi film gupshup. But we&amp;rsquo;re back, with a slightly different version of the podcast.
In this episode, we catch up on films and shows we watched during the time of COVID-19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#80 Female Desire in Bollywood</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/bollywood-female-desire/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/bollywood-female-desire/</guid>
      <description>Episode 80: A look at female desire in Bollywood, with a special guest - Suparna Sharma.
We start off with Geeton Ka Ghanchakkar and Filmi Khabrein.
Then in Bollywood Behes, a conversation with noted Indian film critic and editor Suparna Sharma about how Bollywood films have failed to depict expressions of female desire. This discussion was partly inspired by Suparna&amp;rsquo;s 2013 essay on the same subject.
Music: Bollywood Blades by Professor Kliq/ Material Breakthrough by Peritune</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#79 Bulbbul</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/netflix-bulbbul/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/netflix-bulbbul/</guid>
      <description>Episode 79: A look at the Netflix Original film Bulbbul.
We start off with Geeton Ka Ghanchakkar and Filmi Khabrein.
Then in Bollywood Behes, we look at how Bulbbul takes on patriarchy through the metaphor of a &amp;ldquo;churail&amp;rdquo; and other difficult/nasty women.
Music: Bollywood Blades by Professor Kliq/ Material Breakthrough by Peritune</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#78 Gulabo Sitabo</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/gulabo-sitabo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/gulabo-sitabo/</guid>
      <description>Episode 78: A look at Gulabo Sitabo, the latest film directed by Shoojit Sircar, and written by Juhi Chaturvedi. This director-writer duo has given us films such as Piku, October and Vicky Donor in the past.
We start off with Geeton Ka Ghanchakkar, where we remember veteran Bollywood choreographer Saroj Khan. Filmi Khabrein brings us the latest news in Bollywood.
Then in Bollywood Behes, we look at the world created by language and characters in Gulabo Sitabo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#77 Sushant Singh Rajput</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/sushant-singh-rajput/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/sushant-singh-rajput/</guid>
      <description>Episode 77: A look at the films of Sushant Singh Rajput. The talented Bollywood actor was found dead at his Mumbai home in June 2020. His death was ruled a suicide by Mumbai Police. He was 34.
After making his debut in Bollywood with Kai Po Che (2013), Singh went on to play critically acclaimed roles in films such as M. S. Dhoni - The Untold Story (2016) and Chhichhore (2019).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#76 Never Have I Ever</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/mindy-kaling-netflix-never-have-i-ever/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/mindy-kaling-netflix-never-have-i-ever/</guid>
      <description>Episode 76: A look at Mindy Kaling&amp;rsquo;s Netflix show Never Have I Ever, starring Maitreyi Ramakrishnan.
The show centres around Devi Vishwakumar (Ramaksrishnan), an Indian American teenager growing up in well-heeled California suburb. After a traumatic incident has made her a social pariah, Devi comes back to class with a mission &amp;ndash; to recast herself and her two besties Eleanor Wong (Ramona Young) and Fabiola Torres (Lee Rodriguez) from geek to chic, and get with the high school hottie Paxton Hall-Yoshida (Darren Bennet).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#75 In Memoriam</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/irrfan-rishi-obits/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/irrfan-rishi-obits/</guid>
      <description>Episode 75: Remembering Irrfan Khan and Rishi Kapoor. Although the two actors had very different career paths in the Hindi film industry, they shared a desire to expand their acting repertoire.
Music: Bollywood Blades by Professor Kliq/ Material Breakthrough by Peritune</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#74 Irrfan Khan</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/irrfan-khan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/irrfan-khan/</guid>
      <description>Episode 74: A tribute to Irrfan Khan, celebrated actor who made a mark in both Hindi and international cinema. Khan had been diagnosed with a rare neuroendocrine tumor.
Music: Bollywood Blades by Professor Kliq/ Material Breakthrough by Peritune</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#73 Shubh Mangal Zyada Saavdhan</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/shubh-mangal-zyada-saavdhan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/shubh-mangal-zyada-saavdhan/</guid>
      <description>Episode 73: A look at Shubh Mangal Zyada Saavdhan, starring Ayushmann Khurrana, Jitendra Kumar, Neena Gupta and Gajrao Rao.
We start off with Geeton Ka Ghanchakkar, where we pick songs based on the theme of distances &amp;ndash; literal and metaphorical. Filmi Khabrein delves into upcoming releases on streaming services and how some Bollywood stars are reacting to the global pandemic.
For Bollywood Behes, Aparita and Baisakhi talk about Shubh Mangal Zyada Saavdhan and using the rom-com genre to tell a story about a gay couple seeking acceptance from their family.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#72 R. D. Burman</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/rd-burman/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/rd-burman/</guid>
      <description>Episode 72: A look at the music of R. D. Burman, with Ed Hanley, co-artistic director of Toronto band Autorickshaw.
Burman was one of the most popular Bollywood music composers of the 70&amp;rsquo;s and 80&amp;rsquo;s. His music is popular to this today. In many ways, he was way ahead of his time.
Hanley and his bandmates reprised an R. D. Burman song called &amp;ldquo;Aaj Ki Raat,&amp;rdquo; from the 1973 film Anamika , as part of their 2007 album So The Journey Goes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#71 Bonus: Saloni Gaur</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/kangana-ranaut-bonus-episode/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/kangana-ranaut-bonus-episode/</guid>
      <description>Episode 71 Bonus (Bonus): For this Filmi Funde segment, a chat with Saloni Gaur - a social media star whose riffs on Kangana Ranaut&amp;rsquo;s current affairs hot takes have become viral.
Check out her interpretation of &amp;lsquo;Kangana Runout&amp;rsquo; reacting to the Kunal Kamra and Arnab Goswami confrontation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#71 Kangana Ranaut</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/kangana-ranaut/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/kangana-ranaut/</guid>
      <description>Episode 71: A look at Kangana Ranaut, the Bollywood actress who makes news for her antics on and off the screen.
We start off with Geeton Ka Ghanchakkar, where we choose two songs from films featuring Kangana Ranaut &amp;ndash; an old Asha Bhonsle song, and a travesty from Krrish 3.
For Bollywood Behes, Aparita and Baisakhi talk about Kangana&amp;rsquo;s ability to channel emotionally vulnerable characters as well as her role as a controversy queen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#70 Chhapaak</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/chhapaak-deepika-padukone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/chhapaak-deepika-padukone/</guid>
      <description>Episode 70: A look at Chhapaak, Meghna Gulzar&amp;rsquo;s film inspired by acid attack survivor Laxmi Agarwal and starring Deepika Padukone.
We start off with Geeton Ka Ghanchakkar, where we choose two songs by Gulzar - Meghna&amp;rsquo;s father, celebrated lyricist and erstwhile filmmaker, who also penned the songs for Chhapaak.
For Bollywood Behes, Aparita and Baisakhi talk about their experiences watching Chhapaak. While Aparita appreciated the female solidarity displayed in the film, Baisakhi talked about the ways in which the film reinterprets notions of beauty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#69 Occupy Gateway</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/occupy-gateway/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/occupy-gateway/</guid>
      <description>Episode 69: A conversation with independent filmmaker and writer Asmit Pathare about his experiences of Occupy Gateway.
Music: Untold Tales by Markus Huber Photo: Deepanjana Pal</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#68 NYE Special</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/nye-special/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/nye-special/</guid>
      <description>Episode 68: To ring in the New Year, Aparita and Baisakhi each choose a film they&amp;rsquo;d want to re-watch on their TV screens.
We start off with Geeton Ka Ghanchakkar, where we choose two very different songs that we occasionally groove to. In Filmi Khabrein, we look forward to Hindi movies coming out in 2020 - including Chhapaak, Panga and Thappad.
For Bollywood Behes, Aparita and Baisakhi take it easy and pick two films they wouldn&amp;rsquo;t mind watching again while staying in for NYE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#67 Article 15</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/article-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2019 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/article-15/</guid>
      <description>Episode 67: At a time when many Indians and those in the diaspora have taken to the streets to protest against the Citizenship Amendment Act (CAA), we look at Anubhav Sinha&amp;rsquo;s Article 15.
We start off with Geeton Ka Ghanchakkar, where we remember Bollywood&amp;rsquo;s version of protest songs. In lieu of Filmi Khabrein, Aparita brings you voices from a Toronto protest against the CAA/NRC legislations.
Many people have been talking about the Constitution of India and holding up copies of its preamble at protests and in panel discussions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#66 Mausaji&#39;s Musical Memories</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/mausaji-memories/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/mausaji-memories/</guid>
      <description>Episode 66: A conversation with Aparita&amp;rsquo;s mausaji Bhaskar Khulbe, a Hindi film song lover.
Music: Bollywood Blades by Professor Kliq</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#65 TIFF 2019 Wrap Up</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/tiff-2019-wrap-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/tiff-2019-wrap-up/</guid>
      <description>Episode 65: A conversation about some of the other films and documentaries we watched at Toronto International Film Festival 2019, including Bikram: Yogi, Guru, Predator; Made in Bangladesh and Bombay Rose.
Music: Bollywood Blades by Professor Kliq/Image courtesy TIFF</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#64 TIFF 2019 Moothon</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/tiff-2019-nivin-pauly-moothon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/tiff-2019-nivin-pauly-moothon/</guid>
      <description>Episode 64: A conversation with Geetu Mohandas, Nivin Pauly, Roshan Mathew, Shashank Arora and Shobhita Dhulipala, who brought Moothon to the Toronto International Film Festival 2019.
Music: Bollywood Blades by Professor Kliq/Image courtesy TIFF</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#63 TIFF 2019 The Sky Is Pink</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/tiff-2019-priyanka-chopra/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/tiff-2019-priyanka-chopra/</guid>
      <description>Episode 63: A conversation with Shonali Bose, Priyanka Chopra and Farhan Akhtar, who brought The Sky Is Pink to the Toronto International Film Festival 2019.
Music: Bollywood Blades by Professor Kliq/Image courtesy TIFF</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#62 TIFF 2019 Jallikattu</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/tiff-2019-lijo-jose-pellissery/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/tiff-2019-lijo-jose-pellissery/</guid>
      <description>Episode 62: A conversation with Lijo Jose Pellissery, one of the directors leading the &amp;lsquo;New Generation&amp;rsquo; of Malayalam cinema. Pellissery brought his latest film Jallikattu to the 2019 Toronto International Film Festival.
Music: Bollywood Blades by Professor Kliq</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#61 TIFF 2019 Critics Roundtable</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/tiff-2019-critics-roundtable/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/tiff-2019-critics-roundtable/</guid>
      <description>Episode 61: A conversation with India&amp;rsquo;s leading film critics and writers on the South Asian selection and other remarkable films at 2019 Toronto International Film Festival (TIFF).
We begin with Geeton Ka Ghanchakkar and a quick hit of Filmi Khabrein. And then we bring you a spirited discussion between Namrata Joshi, Aseem Chhabra and Suparna Sharma. The talk about the hits and misses at this year&amp;rsquo;s TIFF, the selection of films from India and other parts of South Asia, and some insight into how they manage festival life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#60 TIFF 2019 Teaser</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/tiff-2019-teaser/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/tiff-2019-teaser/</guid>
      <description>Episode 60: Aparita and Baisakhi are at TIFF 2019, and give you an update on films they have watched so far.
We begin with Geeton Ka Ghanchakkar and a quick hit of Filmi Khabrein. In lieu of Bollywood Behes, Aparita and Baisakhi talk about watching films such as Parasite, Jallikattu and The Sky is Pink, as well as Hollywood films such as Hustlers.
Music: Bollywood Blades by Professor Kliq/ Material Breakthrough by Peritune</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#59 On Vidya Sinha</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/vidya-sinha/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/vidya-sinha/</guid>
      <description>Episode 59: In this episode, a tribute to Vidya Sinha and the modern Hindi film heroine in Rajnigandha and Chhoti Si Baat.
We begin with Geeton Ka Ghanchakkar, remembering Salil Chowdhury and his music. In Filmi Khabrein we talk about three leading ladies in Hindi cinema today, and their upcoming projects - Sonam Kapoor, Taapsee Pannu and Jahnvi Kapoor.
In Bollywood Behes we remember 70&amp;rsquo;s actress Vidya Sinha. The news of her demise last month caught everyone by surprise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#58 On Kashmir</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/kashmir/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/kashmir/</guid>
      <description>Episode 58: In this episode, a look at how Kashmir has been portrayed in Bollywood and Hindi films over the years.
We begin with Geeton Ka Ghanchakkar, paying tribute to older movies set in Kashmir, as well as veteran star Vidya Sinha. Filmi Khabrein returns, in which we talk about Akshay Kumar and other Bollywood celebrities. And then Bollywood Behes takes us into Kashmir, as seen in Hindi cinema.
Given the current political climate, we take a look at the way this disputed territory - one of the world&amp;rsquo;s most militarized zones - has been portrayed as a honeymoon or holiday destination in older Bollywood movies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#57 Jabariya Jodi</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/jabariya-jodi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/jabariya-jodi/</guid>
      <description>Episode 57: In this episode, a conversation with Sanjeev K Jha, the writer of Jabariya Jodi.
He talks about growing up in a small town in Bihar, watching films seriously for the first time as a university student in New Delhi, and writing a film to combat Bihari stereotypes in Indian popular culture.
Music: Bollywood Blades by Professor Kliq</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#56 Soni</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/soni/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/soni/</guid>
      <description>Episode 56: In this episode, a look at Ivan Ayr&amp;rsquo;s debut film Soni. During its debut at Venice International Film Festival, Soni received praise from critics and audiences alike for telling a compelling story about two Indian female police officers, who are trying to maintain a balance between their personal and professional lives. The film has been available to see on Netflix since Jan 2019.
In this conversation, Ivan tells us what led him to filmmaking, influences and approaches, and his desire to understand a &amp;ldquo;dark reality&amp;rdquo; about contemporary Indian society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#55 Leila</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/leila/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/leila/</guid>
      <description>Episode 55: In this episode, a look at Deepa Mehta&amp;rsquo;s Netflix series Leila. We talk about its origins as a book by journalist-turned-author Prayaag Akbar, and why a dystopian series set in India doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be too far from present day reality.
We start off with Geeton Ka Ghanchakkar that features two songs starring Ayushmann Khurrana: Pani Da Rang from Vicky Donor and Moh Moh Ke Dhaage from Dum Laga Ke Haisha.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#54 Kabir Singh</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/kabir-singh/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/kabir-singh/</guid>
      <description>Episode 54: In this episode, despite our better judgement, a look at Kabir Singh. The Hindi remake of the Telugu sleeper hit Arjun Reddy is a bonafide Bollywood blockbuster. We try to understand why this misogynist film has struck a chord with viewers.
We start off with Geeton Ka Ghanchakkar remembering two unique Hindi song takes on the idea of love &amp;ndash; Dil Chahta Hai&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Jaane Kyun&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Man Kyun Behka&amp;rdquo; from Utsav.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#53 Luka Chuppi</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/luka-chuppi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/luka-chuppi/</guid>
      <description>Episode 53: In this episode, a look at Luka Chuppi. Starring Kartik Aaryan and Kriti Sanon, this was the latest Hindi film to explore live-in relationships. It&amp;rsquo;s now available to watch on Netflix.
We start off with Geeton Ka Ghanchakkar with a Tamil twist, featuring two AR Rahman songs: Thaiyya Thaiyya and Mental Manadhil.
Filmi Khabrein covers the latest in Bollywood news, including keeping tabs on the #MeToo movement as well as the the critical reception and box-office success of Kabir Singh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#52 Girish Karnad Legacy</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/girish-karnad-obit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/girish-karnad-obit/</guid>
      <description>Episode 52: In this episode, we pay tribute to veteran playwright, actor, writer and thinker Girish Karnad - who played a starring role both in art house and commercial Hindi/Indian cinema
We start off with Geeton Ka Ghanchakkar featuring two songs to remember Karnad by: a Kannada bhava-geethe Deepavu Ninnade Gaaliyu Ninnade and Mero Gaam Katha Parey. Filmi Khabrein follows, featuring news from the South Indian film industries.
In Bollywood Behes, we look at the important legacy that Karnad has left in Kannada literature and films, as well as his many artistic contributions to Hindi cinema.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#51 Pt. 2 Photograph</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/photograph-corollary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/photograph-corollary/</guid>
      <description>Episode 51 Pt. 2: A special short corollary - Toronto filmmaker Gursimran Datla&amp;rsquo;s analysis of Ritesh Batra&amp;rsquo;s new film Photograph, starring Nawazuddin Siddiqui and Sanya Malhotra.
For more on French filmmaker and philosopher Guy Debord&amp;rsquo;s Society of the Spectacle, see this quick introduction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#51 Photograph</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/photograph/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/photograph/</guid>
      <description>Episode 51: In this episode, a look at Ritesh Batra&amp;rsquo;s new film Photograph, starring Nawazuddin Siddiqui and Sanya Malhotra.
Rafi (Siddiqui) is a street photographer who happens to take a photograph of Miloni (Malhotra) in front of the famous Mumbai tourist spot Gateway of India. Tired of his grandmother&amp;rsquo;s constant refrain to get married, Rafi sends Miloni&amp;rsquo;s photograph to his grandmother saying he&amp;rsquo;s found a girl to marry. When the grandmother announces she&amp;rsquo;s coming to Mumbai to meet the girl, Rafi needs to convince Miloni to play along.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#50 Bhonsle</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/bhonsle-iffsa-toronto/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/bhonsle-iffsa-toronto/</guid>
      <description>Episode 50: In this episode, we record live on location at IFFSA Toronto. We talk about one of the opening films Bhonsle, and kick off a short series called 50-50.
Music: Bollywood Blades by Professor Kliq/ Material Breakthrough by Peritune</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#49 Kalank</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/kalank/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/kalank/</guid>
      <description>Episode 49: In this episode, we unpack our feelings about Kalank, the multi-starrer film featuring Alia Bhatt, Varun Dhawan, Aditya Roy Kapur, Sonakshi Sinha, Madhuri Dixit and Sanjay Dutt among others.
Set against the backdrop of the Partition of India and Pakistan, Kalank attempts to tell the story of love, betrayal and loss. The elaborate family saga starts with Satya (Sonakshi Sinha), who in the face of imminent death due to a disease, persuades Roop (Alia Bhatt) to marry her husband Dev (Aditya Roy Kapur).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#48 Super Deluxe</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/super-deluxe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/super-deluxe/</guid>
      <description>Episode 48: In this episode, a look at Thiagarajan Kumararaja&amp;rsquo;s sophomore film Super Deluxe, starring an ensemble cast that includes Vijay Sethupathi, Samantha Akkineni, Fahadh Faasil, Mysskin, Ramya Krishan, Gayathrie and Ashwanth Ashok Kumar.
Super Deluxe features four separate stories (we mistakenly counted three in our discussion, skipping the story of Leela and Arputham) that come together to form a larger narrative questioning issues such as sexuality, religion, caste and gender - while being both deeply philosophical and irreverent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#47 Party</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/party/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/party/</guid>
      <description>Episode 47: In this episode, a look at Govind Nihalani&amp;rsquo;s cult classic Party, starring an ensemble cast of some the best Indian theatre and art-house actors such as Deepa Sahi, Manohar Singh and Rohini Hattangadi.
The premise of the film is deceptively simple. A celebrated playwright Diwakar Barve (Manohar Singh) has been awarded a prestigious literary award. Socialite Damayanti Rane (Vijaya Mehta) organizes a party to celebrate Barve. A room full of intellectuals soon assemble together, but their conversations mainly centre around missing poet-turned-activist Amrit (Naseeruddin Shah).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#46 Mard Ko Dard Nahi Hota</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/mard-ko-dard-nahi-hota/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/mard-ko-dard-nahi-hota/</guid>
      <description>Episode 46: In this encore presentation, a look at Mard Ko Dard Nahi Hota, directed by Vasan Bala, starring Abhimanyu Dassani, Radhika Madan and Gulshan Devaiah.
Also introducing a new segment called Filmi Funde. In this inaugural version - a conversation with Karan Kulkarni, the music director for Mard Ko Dard Nahi Hota, about three songs from the film.
Music: Bollywood Blades by Professor Kliq</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#45 Made In Heaven</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/made-in-heaven/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/made-in-heaven/</guid>
      <description>Episode 45: Created by Zoya Akhtar and Reema Kagti, co-written by Alankrita Shrivastava, and co-directed by Nitya Mehra and Prashant Nair, Made In Heaven is an Amazon Prime Video series that uses the backdrop of the &amp;lsquo;Big Fat Indian Wedding&amp;rsquo; to talk about social realities.
First we start off with Geeton Ka Ghanchakkar, a shaadi special featuring some unusual shaadi-waali movies - Saathiya and Tanu Weds Manu.
Then Bollywood Behes takes us into the world of modern day Indian weddings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#44 Gully Boy</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/gully-boy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/gully-boy/</guid>
      <description>Episode 44: Gully Boy brought the sounds of Mumbai&amp;rsquo;s gullies to the big Bollywood screen. Directed by Zoya Akhtar, the movie featured A-list stars Ranveer Singh and Alia Bhatt, and a team of formidable supporting actors. Together, they brought to life a story based on the lives of Indian rap stars Divine and Naezy.
First we start off with Geeton Ka Ghanchakkar, which features Bluffmaster&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Right Here Right Now&amp;rdquo; (composed by those hip hop fakers - Vishal and Shekhar) and Baba Sehgal&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Thanda Thanda Pani&amp;rdquo; (yes, we feel your pain).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#43 Ek Ladki Ko Dekha Toh Aisa Laga</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/ek-ladki-ko-dekha-toh-asia-laga/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/ek-ladki-ko-dekha-toh-asia-laga/</guid>
      <description>Episode 43: Aparita Bhandari watched Ek Ladki Ko Dekha Toh Aisa Laga with Queer South Asians and Allies of Toronto (QSAALT). A conversation with its members after watching the movie.
The group talked about queer representation in Bollywood movies of past, and the importance of Ek Ladki Ko Dekha Toh Aisa Laga in giving voice to a mis- or under-represented community.
Then a follow up conversation with Lucky, about her experiences growing up as a lesbian in India.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#42 Arjun Reddy</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/arjun-reddy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/arjun-reddy/</guid>
      <description>Episode 42: A look at the influence of Telugu cinema on Bollywood, and a discussion of the sleeper hit Telugu film Arjun Reddy.
We start off with Geeton Ka Ghanchakkar featuring the hit A. R. Rahman song Urvashi Urvashi, as well as Jumme Ki Raat from Kick. Filmi Khabrein has us talking about Kangana Ranaut and the ensemble cast featured in Total Dhamaal.
In Bollywood Behes, we look at the tradition of Telugu cinema inspiring Bollywood films such as Ek Duje ke Liye, Wanted and Tevar, before discussing Arjun Reddy and its problematic title character.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#41 Uri</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/uri/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/uri/</guid>
      <description>Episode 41: A debate on whether Uri: The Surgical Strike, starring Vicky Kaushal, Yami Gautam and Paresh Rawal among others, is a jingoistic film - or not.
We start off with Geeton Ka Ghanchakkar featuring two A. R. Rahman songs, and Filmi Khabrein full of new teasers and trailer information. Then in Bollywood Behes, an in-depth discussion of how war is made sexy in Uri, including some audience reactions.
Music: Bollywood Blades by Professor Kliq/ Material Breakthrough by Peritune</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#40 Manikarnika - The Queen&#39;s Last Salute</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/manikarnika/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/manikarnika/</guid>
      <description>Episode 40: A conversation with author Moupia Basu on her book The Queen&amp;rsquo;s Last Salute, which is partially inspired by the story of Rani Laxmibai. Basu&amp;rsquo;s book covers much of the same ground as Kangana Ranaut&amp;rsquo;s latest film Manikarnika.
The Queen&amp;rsquo;s Last Salute is published by Juggernaut Books and available at your local bookstore or online.
To see what some of the old monuments at Orchha look like, visit the World Monument Fund website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#39 Simbaa</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/simbaa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/simbaa/</guid>
      <description>Episode 39: We have lots to talk about when it comes to Rohit Shetty and Ranveer Singh&amp;rsquo;s collaboration in Simbaa. While the movie had many fun elements, tacking on a serious issue like rape to a Shetty style masala movie didn&amp;rsquo;t sit well with us.
We start off with Geeton Ka Ghanchakkar, followed by Filmi Khabrein - where we talk about the depiction of police in Shetty&amp;rsquo;s movies and masculinity in Bollywood movies, among other topics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#38 Zero</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/zero/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/zero/</guid>
      <description>Episode 38: We watched Zero, the big budget Anand L. Rai extravaganza starring Bollywood superstar Shah Rukh Khan, alongside top-billing female leads Anushka Sharma and Katrina Kaif. The movie didn&amp;rsquo;t impress us much; but then neither did Race 3 or Thugs of Hindostan earlier in 2018. So, this episode features our experience of watching Zero, followed by a discussion on the relevance of Bollywood&amp;rsquo;s Khan triumverate.
We start off with Geeton Ka Ghanchakkar, followed by Filmi Khabrein - where we note the passing of two Indian cinema greats: veteran art house filmmaker Mrinal Sen, and Bollywood screenwriter and actor Kader Khan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#37 Vivek</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/vivek/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/vivek/</guid>
      <description>Episode 37: In this special episode, a conversation with celebrated Indian documentary filmmaker Anand Patwardhan about his latest work Vivek/Reason.
Vivek/Reason screened as part of the Toronto International Film Festival (2018). Although many balked at first at its run-time &amp;ndash; the 261 minute long documentary is meant to be screened in two sessions &amp;ndash; critics noted its importance, especially given the rise of nationalistic rhetoric in India and across the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#36 Stree</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/stree/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/stree/</guid>
      <description>Episode 36: In this episode, a look at Stree. This horror-comedy film starring Rajkummar Rao, Shraddha Kapoor, Aparshakti Khurrana, Abhishek Banerjee and Pankaj Tripathi was a sleeper hit, telling an unusual story of an evil female spirit who kidnaps men.
Although the film used the horror-comedy genre to address themes such as patriarchy and consent in an amusing and innovative fashion &amp;ndash; stale jokes, lazy writing and a meandering script watered down its central thesis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#35 Badhaai Ho</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/badhaai-ho/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/badhaai-ho/</guid>
      <description>Episode 35: In this episode, a look at Badhaai Ho, starring Ayushmann Khurrana, Sanya Malhotra, Neena Gupta, Gajraj Rao and Surekha Sikri. Although Hindi films typically centre around its younger stars, Badhaai Ho featured stand-out performances by the senior artists, stealing scene after scene, in a film that broached the topic of parental sex with gentle humour and tons of grace.
All of this after a round of Geeton Ka Ghanchakkar featuring two classic Hindi tunes, and a Filmi Khabrein round-up of the latest Bollywood news.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#34 AndhaDhun</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/andhadhun/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/andhadhun/</guid>
      <description>Episode 34: A look at Sriram Raghavan&amp;rsquo;s body of work that leads up to his latest film, AndhaDhun - starring Ayushmann Khurrana, Tabu and Radhika Apte.
Music: Bollywood Blades by Professor Kliq/ Material Breakthrough by Peritune</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#33 Bollywood Romcoms</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/bollywood-romcom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2018 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/bollywood-romcom/</guid>
      <description>Episode 33: We are back to our regular programming! In this episode, inspired by the Netflix hit To All The Boys I Loved Before, Aparita and Baisakhi pick their favourite contemporary Bollywood romcom aimed at young people.
While romance is always an ingredient in popular Hindi films, Bollywood romcoms are a genre unto themselves. Contemporary Hindi cinema has given us plenty of movies to choose from, even if the gender politics remain somewhat problematic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#32 Bollywood #MeToo</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/bollywood-metoo-janice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/bollywood-metoo-janice/</guid>
      <description>Episode 32: In this special episode, a conversation with Janice Sequeira, a former broadcast journalist and entertainment reporter, about Bollywood&amp;rsquo;s leading role in India&amp;rsquo;s #MeToo movement.
Music: Bollywood Blades by Professor Kliq</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#31 TIFF Manto</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/tiff-2018-manto/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/tiff-2018-manto/</guid>
      <description>Episode 31: A conversation with Nandita Das, who brought her second feature film Manto to TIFF 2018.
After Geeton Ka Ghanchakkar and Filmi Khabrein, we also talk to Urdu-Hindi writer Faiyaz Ahmad Wajeeh as part of Bollywood Behes about his take on Das&#39; bio-pic Manto. Well-versed with Manto&amp;rsquo;s prolific writings, Wajeeh was disappointed with what he saw as the film&amp;rsquo;s mischaracterization of the celebrated Urdu writer Manto. If you want to know more about Manto, says Wajeeh, just read his many stories and essays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#30 TIFF Mard Ko Dard Nahi Hota</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/tiff-2018-mard-ko-dard/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/tiff-2018-mard-ko-dard/</guid>
      <description>Episode 30: Our second TIFF-related episode features a conversation with Vasan Bala and Abhimanyu Dassani, the director and star respectively of Mard Ko Dard Nahi Hota, aka The Man Who Feels No Pain.
After Geeton Ka Ghanchakkar, inspired by Bollywood&amp;rsquo;s take on karate and the festive season, and Filmi Khabrein, where we talk about Rima Das&amp;rsquo;s film Village Rockstars being submitted as India&amp;rsquo;s entry to the Oscars among other news, we feature Vasan&amp;rsquo;s sophomore feature in Bollywood Behes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#29 TIFF Critics Roundtable</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/tiff-2018-roundtable/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/tiff-2018-roundtable/</guid>
      <description>Episode 29: We kick off our TIFF-related episodes with a critics rountable. One of the world&amp;rsquo;s best known film festivals, Toronto International Film Festival has long been a friend to Hindi and other Indian films. This year, along with the films, came a contingent of Indian film critics. We had a chance to speak with four of them about their thoughts on TIFF 2018.
The rountable was made up of: Shubhra Gupta, film critic for The Indian Express, and author of 50 Films That Changed Bollywood; Namrata Joshi, cinema editor and film critic for The Hindu; Suparna Sharma, film critic for The Asian Age and Deccan Chronicle; and Aseem Chhabra, film journalist and author of Priyanka Chopra: The Incredible Story of a Global Bollywood Star.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#28 TIFF 2018 Teaser</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/tiff-2018-teaser/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/tiff-2018-teaser/</guid>
      <description>Episode 28: In this special episode, a teaser from TIFF 2018. One of the world&amp;rsquo;s best known film festivals, Toronto International Film Festival has long been a friend to Hindi and other Indian films. This year was no different, with films such as Manto, Manmarziyaan and Mard Ko Dard Nahin Hota headlining the roster.
We present a short report from the festival grounds that looks forward to coming episodes featuring interviews with filmmakers, our reactions to the films and a critics roundtable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#27 Bhavesh Joshi Superhero</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/bhavesh-joshi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/bhavesh-joshi/</guid>
      <description>Episode 27: Bhavesh Joshi Superhero is Vikramaditya Motwane&amp;rsquo;s latest feature film, and stars Harshvardhan Kapoor among an ensemble cast of stellar character actors. Inspired by the superhero/vigilante figures from graphic novels, Motwane tells a contemporary tale that also serves as an origin story of a homegrown Indian superhero/vigilante.
It starts off innocently enough. Three friends - Bhavesh, Sikander or Sikku and Rajat - flirt with India&amp;rsquo;s protest culture. But Sikku soon gets disenchanted, and Rajat busy with his job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#25 Karwaan</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/karwaan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/karwaan/</guid>
      <description>Episode 25: Karwaan is an offbeat addition to Bollywood&amp;rsquo;s genre of road trip movies. Starring Dulquer Salmaan, Irrfan Khan and Mithila Palkar, it follows the unusual friendship that evolves between three seemingly disconnected people.
To please his father, Avinash (Dulquer) keeps working a soulless job, although he&amp;rsquo;d much rather pursue his passion for photography. An unexpected phone call informs him of his father&amp;rsquo;s death in a bus accident and sets the road trip in motion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#24 Dhadak</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/dhadak/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/dhadak/</guid>
      <description>Episode 24: A look at Dhadak, a Hindi film adaptation which launched Bollywood progeny Janhvi Kapoor and Ishaan Khattar, but downplayed the issue of caste raised in the original Marathi film Sairat.
While discussing how Hindi films have depicted caste in the past, we revisit films such as Sujata, the 1960 Bimal Roy classic which also went to Cannes; Ankur, a debut for Shyam Benegal as director and Shabana Azmi and Anant Nag as actors; and Newton, starring Rajkummar Rao, this film by Amit Masurkar explores the state of Indian democracy today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#23 Varun Grover</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/varun-grover/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/varun-grover/</guid>
      <description>Episode 23: A conversation with Varun Grover, the Indian National Award winning lyricist, writer and stand-up comedian.
After penning songs such as Moh Moh Ke Dhaage in the film Dum Laga Ke Haisha (2015), for which he won the Indian National Award for best lyrics, and writing Masaan (2015), which won the FIPRESCI award at Cannes Film Festival among other accolades, Varun has been recently fielding interview requests from across the world for his role as lead writer in Netflix India&amp;rsquo;s first original series Sacred Games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#22 Sacred Games</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/sacred-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/sacred-games/</guid>
      <description>Episode 22: Netflix India original series Sacred Games has been getting lots of acclaim from critics and audiences alike. Starring Nawazuddin Siddiqui and Saif Ali Khan in main roles, alongside a stellar supporting cast, it is directed by Hindi cinema heavyweights Vikramaditya Motwane and Anurag Kashyap.
Sacred Games is adapted from Vikram Chandra&amp;rsquo;s 2006 novel, a 900-page tome. The series stays true to the spirit of the novel, which takes us into the labyrinthine depths of Mumbai, where religion and politics are bigger games than drugs and guns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#21 Gopal Das Neeraj Songs</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/neeraj/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/neeraj/</guid>
      <description>Episode 21: In this special episode, a conversation with documentary filmmaker, writer and critic Paromita Vohra on the Hindi film songs legacy of renowned poet Gopal Das Neeraj. Often simply referred to as Neeraj, he died on 19 July 2018. He was 93.
Using the songs Neeraj wrote for the Navketan Films&#39; production Prem Pujari, Paromita tells us what made Neeraj&amp;rsquo;s songs stand apart from his contemporaries.
Music: Prem Pujari (OST)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#20 Film Critics: Shubhra Gupta and Aseem Chhabra</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/shubhra-aseem/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/shubhra-aseem/</guid>
      <description>Episode 20: In this special episode, a conversation with Indian Express film critic Shubhra Gupta and Bollywood biographer Aseem Chhabra.
Shubhra Gupta has been covering Hindi films and other movies for decades. She&amp;rsquo;s the author of 50 Films That Changed Bollywood. Besides authoring two biographies - Shashi Kapoor: The Householder, the Star and Priyanka Chopra: The Incredible Story of a Global Bollywood Star - Aseem Chhabra also curates several film festivals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#19 On Sanjay Dutt</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/sanjay-dutt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 04:10:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/sanjay-dutt/</guid>
      <description>Episode 19: In this special episode, Yasser Usman talks about his unauthorized biography of Sanjay Dutt, and we meet one of the star’s biggest fans in Toronto.
Yasser Usman grew up watching Hindi films and admiring Sanjay Dutt’s sense of style in movies such as Naam and Saajan. After writing the unauthorized biographies of Rajesh Khanna and Rekha, he wrote his third book on Sanjay Dutt. Listen to a conversation with Yasser about the star and the biopic inspired by his life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#18 Sanju</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/sanju/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 04:10:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/sanju/</guid>
      <description>Episode 18: Sanju purports to give audiences the true story of Sanjay Dutt, told straight by Sanju baba himself, warts and all &amp;ndash; no intermediaries or anonymous sources. Why is the film so superficial then?
In fact, Sanju takes far more cinematic liberties than the disclaimer at the beginning of the movie outlines. It glamourizes his questionable behaviour and glosses over major chunks of his troubled life. So is this a true biopic or wishful thinking on both Sanjay Dutt and Rajkumar Hirani&amp;rsquo;s part?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#17 Lust Stories</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/lust-stories/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 04:10:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/lust-stories/</guid>
      <description>Episode 17: After Bombay Talkies (2013), four famous Bollywood or Hindi cinema directors - Anurag Kashyap, Zoya Akhtar, Dibakar Banerjee and Karan Johar - come together to make a Netflix special, a four film anthology called Lust Stories.
Anurag Kashyap presents a female questioning of monogamy; Zoya Akhtar puts a spin on two tropes: &amp;ldquo;friends with benefits&amp;rdquo; as well as the shaadi-ka-rishta scene; Dibakar Banerjee unpacks an extramarital affair between college-friends; Karan Johar gives new meanings to eating ice-cream.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#16 Veere Di Wedding</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/veere-di-wedding/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 04:10:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/veere-di-wedding/</guid>
      <description>Episode 16: In what is likely a Bollywood first, Veere Di Wedding brings the story of four childhood female friends to screen. Yes! Girls can have fun, and make a box-office hit too! The film stars Kareena Kapoor Khan, Sonam K. Ahuja, Swara Bhaskar and Shikha Talsania.
While bromances have long been depicted in Bollywood, ranging from an adult friendship in Sholay to childhood friends in Dil Chahta Hai or Zindagi Na Milegi Dobara, it is unusual to see meaningful female friendships in Hindi cinema.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#15 7 Din Mohabbat In</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/7din/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 04:10:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/7din/</guid>
      <description>Episode 15: In this special episode, a conversation with celebrated Pakistani actors Mahira Khan and Sheheryar Munawar Siddiqui about their latest film 7 Din Mohabbat In, which releases on 15 June 2018, in time for Eid celebrations.
This romantic comedy tells the story of a young man Tipu (Sheheryar Munawar Siddiqui) who in unable to stand up for himself, and his cousin and confidante Neeli (Mahira Khan), who is also in love with him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#14 Raazi</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/raazi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 04:10:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/raazi/</guid>
      <description>Episode 14: Based on a true story, Raazi brings an unlikely female spy to the big screen. When Bangladesh sought to secede from Pakistan, India got involved in a military confrontation that came to be known as the Indo-Pakistani War of 1971. At the time, a young Kashmiri woman Sehmat Khan married into a Pakistani general&amp;rsquo;s family at the request of her father, who himself was a Kashmiri businessman and spy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#13 Sonu Ke Titu Ki Sweety</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/sktks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 04:10:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/sktks/</guid>
      <description>Episode 13: Are Luv Ranjan films such as Pyaar Ka Punchnama and Sonu Ke Titu Ki Sweety misogynistic? Aparita and Baisakhi debate in two episodes. In #13, a look at Sonu Ke Titu Ki Sweety. This movie marks the return of Kartik Aaryan and Nushrat Bharucha along with Sunny Singh Nijjar in yet another Luv Ranjan bromance, this time set against a shaadi ka backdrop.
In Geeton Ka Ghanchakkar listen to Lehmber Hussainpuri&amp;rsquo;s popping track Sadi Gali from Tanu Weds Manu (2011), and the gentle duet from Abhimaan (1973) Teri Bindiya Re, sung by Mohd.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#12 Pyaar Ka Punchnama</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/punchnama/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 04:10:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/punchnama/</guid>
      <description>Episode 12: Are Luv Ranjan films such as Pyaar Ka Punchnama and Sonu Ke Titu Ki Sweety misogynistic? Aparita and Baisakhi debate &amp;ndash; in two episodes. In #12, a look at Pyaar Ka Punchnama. This movie has been described as a battle of the sexes comedy, which made director Luv Ranjan, and actors Kartik Aaryan and Nushrat Bharucha into household names in India.
In Geeton Ka Ghanchakkar we take a cue from the start of shaadi ka season and listen to AR Rahman&amp;rsquo;s track Mehndi Hai Rachne Wali from Zubeidaa (2001), and another ladies sangeet hit Sheila Ki Jawani, a Vishal-Shekhar composition from Tees Maar Khan (2010).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#11 Shakespeare Wallah</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/shakespearewallah/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 04:10:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/shakespearewallah/</guid>
      <description>Episode 11: A look at Tungrus, a contemporary Indian documentary, and Shakespeare Wallah, the Merchant-Ivory classic starring Shashi Kapoor, Felicity Kendal and Madhur Jaffray.
In Geeton Ka Ghanchakkar we listen once again to some golden oldies starring Shashi Kapoor: Khilte Hain Gul Yahan from Sharmilee (1971) and Raat Baaki from Namak Halaal (1982).
Filmi Khabrein has a discussion of the upcoming Bollywood shaadi/wedding extravangza movie Veere Di Wedding, another quick take on Vikramaditya Motwane’s new film Bhavesh Joshi and Javed Akhtar calling out &amp;lsquo;creative vandalism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#10 October</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/october/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 04:10:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/october/</guid>
      <description>Episode 10: Shoojit Sircar’s latest film October contemplates the journey of Dan (Varun Dhawan) as he comes to appreciate his life while facing his colleague Shiuli’s (Banita Sandhu) brush with death.
A quick round of Geeton Ka Ghanchakkar considers Manmarziyan from Lootera (2013) and Manwa from October. Filmi Khabrein has a quick discussion of the upcoming Sanjay Dutt bio-pic Sanju, Vikramaditya Motwane’s new film Bhavesh Joshi and the reuniting of a popular Bollywood on-screen pair.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#9 Cake</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 04:10:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/cake/</guid>
      <description>Episode 9: Starring Sanam Saeed and Aamina Sheikh in leading roles, Asim Abbasi’s debut film Cake steps away from the traditional formula of Pakistani films.
Cake tells us the layered story of the Jamali family. Zareen (Aamina Sheikh), the middle child, has had to abandon her baking dreams and take care of aging parents Siraj (Moahmmed Ahmed) and Habiba (Beo Raana Zafar), while younger sister Zara (Sanam Saeed) and older brother Zain (Faris Khalid) pursue their lives in London and New York City respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#8 Blackmail</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/blackmail/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 04:10:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/blackmail/</guid>
      <description>Episode 8: Irrfan Khan&amp;rsquo;s latest film Blackmail has been billed as a dark comedy. Early reviews also called it a satire on marriage. Aparita and Baisakhi discuss whether the movie truly lives up to the potential of its premise.
Blackmail revolves around the story of Dev (Irrfan Khan) who discovers his wife Reena (Kirti Kulhari) is having an affair and decides to blackmail her lover Ranjit (Arunoday Singh). While Bollywood and other Hindi films often hold up marriage as a sacred institution, the topic of marital infidelity has been explored in movies such as Silsila, Ijaazat and Kabhi Alvida Naa Kehna.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#7 Farooq Sheikh</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/farooq/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 04:10:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/farooq/</guid>
      <description>Episode 7: A special episode on Farooq Sheikh. With Baisakhi Roy away on vacation, Aparita Bhandari looks at the work of the veteran Bollywood actor, beloved by his fans, who died of a heart attack on 28 December 2013.
Chashme Badoor is likely the most well-known of Farooq Sheikh&amp;rsquo;s movies. The cult romantic comedy was known for its simple and charming story, which was brilliantly acted by the ensemble cast. But he also starred in many other films including Saath Saath, Katha, and Kissi Se Na Kehna, to name a few.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#6 Hichki</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/hichki/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 04:10:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/hichki/</guid>
      <description>Episode 6: Hichki marks the return of Rani Mukherji in the role of a teacher with Tourette Syndrome. After a round of Geeton Ka Ghanchakkar and Filmi Khabrein, we discuss how disability has been portrayed in Bollywood films in our main segment Bollywood Behes.
Inspired by the book Front of the Class, and based on the real life story of an American teacher Brad Cohen, Hichki tells the story of a woman passionate about teaching despite the challenges presented by her neurological disorder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#5 Pyaasa</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/pyaasa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 04:10:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/pyaasa/</guid>
      <description>Episode 5: In our fifth episode, we look at Pyaasa, a cult classic Bollywood film. After a round of Geeton Ka Ghanchakkar (The Pyaasa Edition) and Filmi Khabrein, we discuss what makes Pyaasa such an iconic Hindi film as part of our main segment Bollywood Behes.
Pyaasa is widely considered one of Hindi cinema&amp;rsquo;s path-breaking films. Made in 1957, the film was made in the vein of art-house films but was also commercially successful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/host/broy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 23:44:46 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/host/broy/</guid>
      <description>Baisakhi Roy is a seasoned reporter, editor and writer with more than 10 years experience in print and online mediums. Her passion is to put out engaging and compelling content for readers who want to be informed and entertained. A true-blue Bambaiyya, she loves all things Bollywood!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/host/abhandari/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 23:41:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/host/abhandari/</guid>
      <description>Aparita Bhandari is an arts/life journalist based out of Toronto. She regularly contributes to a wide range of media outlets, both print and radio; check out her website www.aparita.com for more information. Despite her many distractions (knitting, fountain pens, baking), Bollywood and Toblerone bars have been two constants in her life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#4 Pari</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/pari/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 04:10:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/pari/</guid>
      <description>Episode 4: In our fourth episode, we look at Pari and Bollywood&amp;rsquo;s latest take on the horror film genre. After a round of Geeton Ka Ghanchakkar (The Horror Edition) and Filmi Khabrein, we discuss how Pari fits into the Bollywood horror films tradition as part of our main segment Bollywood Behes.
Prosit Roy&amp;rsquo;s debut film Pari, starring Anushka Sharma, is Bollywood&amp;rsquo;s latest foray into horror films. However, where previous Bollywood horror movies produced by the likes of the Ramsay Brothers and Ram Gopal Verma depended on sex and jump cut scares, Roy wanted to tread down the same atmospheric horror path as the classic horror film The Shining.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#3 Remembering Sridevi</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/sridevi-tribute/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 04:10:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/sridevi-tribute/</guid>
      <description>Episode 3: In our third episode, we pay tribute to Bollywood icon Sridevi. After a round of Geeton Ka Ghanchakkar dedicated to famous songs featuring Sridevi and Filmi Khabrein, we discuss the Bollywood star&amp;rsquo;s legacy as part of our main segment Bollywood Behes.
The news of Sridevi&amp;rsquo;s death on 24 Feb 2018 left her fans shocked. The Bollywood veteran actress had recently returned to the big screen after a 15 year break, starring in movies such as English Vinglish and Mom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#2 Aiyyary</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/aiyyary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 04:10:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/aiyyary/</guid>
      <description>Episode 2: In our second episode, after a round of Geeton Ka Ghanchakkar (where we discuss Bollywood songs stuck in our heads) and Filmi Khabrein, we discuss Bollywood’s spy films in our main segment Bollywood Behes.
Following the release of Aiyyary, Neeraj Pandey’s riff on the famous Adarsh Housing Society scam, we look at the legacy of spy movies in Hindi cinema &amp;ndash; looking at CID (1956), Farz (1967), Ankhen (1968), Ek Tha Tiger (2012), Baby (2015) and Tiger Zinda Hai (2017).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#1 Pad Man</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/padman/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 04:10:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/padman/</guid>
      <description>In the debut episode, Aparita and Baisakhi introduce Khabardaar podcast, play a minute-long round of antaakshari, brief you on some Bollywood news, and then move on to the main segment &amp;ndash; Bollywood Behes.
Aparita and Baisakhi discuss the recently released Bollywood movie Pad Man, featuring Akshay Kumar, along with Radhika Apte and Sonam Kapoor; it&amp;rsquo;s based on the real life story of Arunachalam Murugunantham. They talk about Pad Man as a PSA (public service announcement movie), and the types of questions it raises (or not) while trying to create awareness about menstruation and sanitary napkins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Khabardaar!</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/teaser/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 04:10:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/teaser/</guid>
      <description>In this teaser, Aparita and Baisakhi discuss the first time they watched a Bollywood movie. Just so you know that they know their filmi stuff.
Music: Bollywood Blades by Professor Kliq/ Material Breakthrough by Peritune</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2016 02:11:48 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Khabardaar Podcast is a Hindi language show presented by Aparita Bhandari and Baisakhi Roy, two Toronto-based arts/life journalists. Lifelong Bollywood fans, Aparita and Baisakhi talk about what’s going on in the Hindi film industry, and discuss themes explored to Bollywood films. Subscribe for your fix!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/soorma-gold-hockey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khabardaarpodcast.com/soorma-gold-hockey/</guid>
      <description>aliases = [&amp;quot;/26&amp;quot;] author = &amp;ldquo;Aparita&amp;rdquo; categories = [] date = &amp;ldquo;2018-08-29T00:00:17-04:00&amp;rdquo; episode = &amp;ldquo;26&amp;rdquo; episode_image = &amp;ldquo;img/episode/ep26mq.jpg&amp;rdquo; explicit = &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo; images = [&amp;ldquo;img/episode/ep26mq.jpg&amp;rdquo;] news_keywords = [] podcast_duration = &amp;ldquo;0:54:27&amp;rdquo; podcast_file = &amp;ldquo;khabardaar-20180829-soorma-gold.mp3&amp;rdquo; podcast_bytes = &amp;quot;&amp;quot; tags = [] title = &amp;ldquo;#26 Soorma + Gold&amp;rdquo; youtube = &amp;quot;&amp;quot; +++
Episode 26: A look at hockey as depicted in recent Bollywood films such as Soorma and Gold, which also reminded audiences of the 2007 Shah Rukh Khan starrer Chak De India.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
